culturess.com 2019-06-24

# FanSided - Sports News, Entertainment, Lifestyle & Technology - 300+ Sites

### _This Privacy Policy is effective on February 22, 2019._

This Privacy Policy describes how FanSided (“ **FanSided** ,” “ **we** ,” “ **our,** ” or “ **us** ”) collects, uses, and shares the personal information you provide to us on our FanSided network of websites: <https://fansided.com/network/>, <https://swag.fansided.com/>, our network of mobile device applications (the “Apps”), or other services, and applies to your use of any online service location that posts a link to this Privacy Policy and all features, content, and other services that we own, control, and make available through such online service location (collectively, the “ **Service** ”). It also describes your rights and choices regarding our use and sharing of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to our information collection activities outside of the Service (unless otherwise stated below or at the time of collection).

Advertisements displayed to you when you use our Service and elsewhere may be customized and targeted to your interests and preferences based on your information collected through our Service. For more information on advertising and your rights and choices, see the section entitled “Your Rights and Choices” below.

By using the Service, you agree to our [Terms of Use](https://fansided.com/terms-of-use/)  and to our collection, use and disclosure practices, and other activities as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree and consent, discontinue use of the Service.

If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please contact us as set forth in the section entitled “Contact Us” below.

 **1.  Collection of Information**

 **A.     Information That You Provide**

We collect information from you, which may include personal information, when you:

  * subscribe to one of our online newsletters, our FanSided custom daily newsletter, or our FanSided Swag newsletter;
  * download and register to use one of our Apps or other Services;
  * create a FanSided Swag store account,
  * apply to be a site expert, editor, contributor, writer, or other type of FanSided content provider, as well as any job opportunity;
  * submit content to or through the Service including through comments, the FanSided Story Tipline, or to any FanSided network address, both physical and electronic;
  * respond to one of our polls, surveys, votes, rankings or by otherwise expressing an opinion;
  * play games and take quizzes;
  * participate in one of our online forums or communities;
  * enter into a contest, sweepstakes, or other promotion;
  * purchase, return, or exchange products, swag, or tickets offered through the Service;
  * browse and review our products and swag; or
  * contact us through any FanSided network address or our customer service department with an enquiry, comment, or suggestion.

Some of the information we request from you is required in order for you to use our Service. If you do not wish to provide such information to us, you are not obligated to, but as a result you may not be able to use the particular Service or certain features. However, some of the personal information we request from you is optional. This means that you can elect not to provide it to us and you will still be able to use the Service.

The types of information that may be collected at these pages and elsewhere include but are not limited to:

  * Contact data including your first and last name, e-mail address, postal address, phone number, and other similar contact data.
  * Credentials such as passwords, password hints, and similar security information for authentication and account access.
  * Demographic information such as your age, birthdate, gender, and country.
  * Payment data such as your payment instrument number (such as a credit card number) and the security code associated with your payment instrument, billing information including your name and address, and FanSided account details. We collect this data in order to process your payments for purchases, fulfill your requests for refunds, returns, or exchanges, and process the redemption of discounts.
  * If applicable, your username, interests, favorites, and other profile data including your enrollment in a FanSided Swag account.
  * The content of messages you send to us, such as feedback, suggestions, comments, or questions and any information you provide to customer support. We also collect the content of your communications as necessary to provide you with the services you use. For example, if you chat with another user through the Service, we need to collect the content of that chat to display it to you and the other user as you direct.
  * Data that you may send us in order to consider you for a job opening, or a content providing position including writer, site expert, or editor if you submit an application to us, such as contact, your employment history, transcript, writing samples, references, interests, and other information.

We may also collect information about your personal or professional interests and use of or opinions about various products, programs and services. You may choose to voluntarily submit other information to us through the Service that we do not request, and, in such instances, you are solely responsible for such information.

 _ **Promotions or Surveys**_. When you enter a contest or sweepstakes (“Promotion”) or participate in a survey or poll (“Survey”) we ask you to provide your name, address, phone number and e-mail address. We use the information we collect on promotion entry forms to administer your participation in the promotions and for other purposes stated on the entry form. Our surveys ask for opinions on various issues and may be sponsored by our advertisers and partners. Information obtained through surveys is also aggregated and used internally.

 _ **Public Information**_. Certain areas of the Service, such as comments, are designed to help you share information with the world. Please remember that any information you disclose in public forums, community areas, and article comments becomes public information and is immediately accessible to other users, so it is important for you to carefully consider what, if any, personal information you reveal in these areas as you are solely responsible for any information you make public. We may use information disclosed by you in this way to promote our products and services in our advertising communications, among other things. Once you have posted information, you may not be able to edit or delete such information; however, California residents have additional rights as set forth in the section entitled “ **Your Rights and Choices** ” below.

 **B.     Information Collected Automatically**

We automatically collect information about your device and how your device interacts with our Service. We may use Service Providers to collect this information. Some examples of information we collect include the following:

  *  **Service Use Data**. We collect data about the features you use, the pages you visit, the e-mails and advertisements you view, the products you purchase, the time of day you browse, the videos you view, your referring and exiting pages, and other similar information.
  *  **Device Connectivity and Configuration Data**. We collect data about the type of device or browser you use, your device’s operating software, your internet service provider, your device’s regional and language settings, and other similar information. This data also includes IP address, MAC address, device advertising ID (e.g., IDFA or AAID), and other device identifiers.
  *  **Mobile Device IDs and Location-Based Information**. Certain mobile devices, including smart phones and tablet devices, contain unique device IDs that can be used to identify their physical location. Some mobile device IDs are persistent, while others may be resettable by accessing the device’s privacy settings. Mobile devices also typically transmit caller ID data (which may include a phone number) when used to transmit a telephone call or text message. When you use mobile devices to access our Services, we may collect and transmit unique device IDs and collect caller ID data, as well as other information about your device, including without limitation, your wireless carrier, the make, model, operating system, capacity and settings of your device, the names, package IDs and versions of other software you have downloaded to your device and information about how you interact with and navigate within our Service. With your consent, we or our authorized service providers and partners also may use precise geolocation technology such as GPS or Wi-Fi triangulation or mobile Bluetooth beacon technology to collect information about the exact location of your mobile device. Precise location information may be collected both while you are using one of our mobile applications and continuously over time while our apps are not in use but are running in the background of your device. You can withdraw your consent to the further collection and use of your precise device location data through any of our mobile apps by accessing your device’s privacy settings as further explained below in “ **Your Rights and Choices: Location-Identifying Technologies.** ” For information about how to reset your advertising identifier and your other opt-out choices relating to interest-based advertising in mobile applications, see “ **Your Rights and Choices: Mobile App Advertising and Tracking**.”

We use various technologies to collect this information (“ **Tracking Technologies** ”), including the following:

  *  **Log Files**. A log file is a file that records events that occur in connection with your use of the Service, such as your service use data.
  *  **Cookies**. A cookie is a small data file stored on your device that acts as a unique tag to identify your browser. We use several types of cookies including session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate the Service and expire when you close your browser. Persistent cookies help with personalizing your experience, remembering your preferences, and supporting security features. Additionally, persistent cookies allow us to bring you advertising both on and off the Service. Persistent cookies may remain on your device for extended periods of time, and generally may be controlled through your browser settings.
  *  **Pixels**. A pixel (also known as a web beacon) is code embedded in a website, video, e-mail, or advertisements that sends information about your use to a server. There are various types of pixels, including image pixels (which are small graphic images) and JavaScript pixels (which contains JavaScript code). When you access a website, video, e-mail, or advertisement that contains a pixel, the pixel may permit us or a third party to drop or read cookies on your browser. Pixels are used in combination with cookies to track activity by a particular browser on a particular device. We may incorporate pixels from third parties that allow us track our conversions, bring you advertising both on and off the Service, and provide you with additional functionality, such as the ability to connect our Service with your social media account.
  *  **Device Fingerprinting**. Device fingerprinting is the process of analyzing and combining sets of information elements from your device’s browser, such as JavaScript objects and installed fonts, in order to create a “fingerprint” of your device and uniquely identify your device and apps.
  *  **App Technologies, Customization, and Usage**. There are a variety of tracking technologies that may be included in our apps that allow us to collect information about your installation, use, and updating of our Apps as well as information about your device, including your unique device identifier (“ **UDID** ”) and other technical identifiers. More specifically, these tracking technologies allow us to collect data about your device and your use of our Apps, the pages, videos, other content, or ads you see or click on during your visit and when and for how long you do so, and items you download. These tracking technologies are not browser-based like cookies and cannot be controlled by browser settings. For example, our apps may include third party SDKs, which is code that sends information about your use to a server, and is in effect the app version of a pixel. These SDKs allow us to track our conversions and communicate with you across devices, bring you advertising both on and off the Service, customize the app to your interests and preferences and link such across platforms and devices, and provide you with additional functionality, such as the ability to connect our Service with your social media account.
  *  **Location-Identifying Technologies**. GPS, WiFi, Bluetooth, and other location-aware technologies may be used to collect precise location data when you enable location-based services through your device. Location data may be used for purposes such as verifying your device’s location and delivering or restricting relevant content and advertising based on that location.
  *  **Voice Processing Technologies**. Voice processing technologies collect audio through the microphone on your device(s) to effectuate an instruction or request by you using Amazon Alexa Skills or Google Assistant. Please be aware that your use of Amazon Alexa Skills or Google Assistant may provide Amazon and Google with access to and use of information associated with your use of their device, including the audio you provide, and you should carefully review their privacy policy and terms of use. If you activate or use this functionality we will process the following data:
    * The serial number of your devices;
    * Functional characteristics and the status of your devices;
    * Data about how you interact with Alexa Skills or Google Assistant, including how often and where you use voice processing technology;
    * The content of your conversation in the form of transcripts; and
    * Personally identifiable features for telecommunications.

We process the data for the following purposes:

    * To ensure interaction and functionality of FanSided features with Alexa Skills and Google Assistant;
    * To offer you the appropriate service as requested through voice processing technology;
    * To improve our product and service offerings (for example, programs, features, and other functions used);
    * To contact you for the purposes of targeted offers of services and products tailored to your interests; and
    * To provide and enhance the user experience of our Alexa Skills and Google Assistant capabilities.

We may use non-audio data associated with your use of voice processing technologies for additional purposes such as data analytics and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Some information about your use of the Service and certain Third Party Services (defined below) may be collected using Tracking Technologies across time and services and used by us and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and deliver relevant ads and/or other content to you on the Service and certain Third Party Services.

For further information on Tracking Technologies and your rights and choices regarding them, see the sections entitled “Third Parties” and “Your Rights and Choices” below.

 **C.   Information Collected from Other Sources**

We combine personal information collected through the Service with other information that we obtain about you, your computer, and/or device from other companies and sources. To the extent we combine personal information collected through the Service with information we obtain from third party sources, we will treat the combined data in accordance with the practices described in this Privacy Policy, plus any additional restrictions imposed by the source of the data. These third party sources vary over time, but have included:

  * Data brokers from which we purchase demographic data to supplement the data we collect;
  * Social networks when you reference our Service or grant permission to FanSided to access your data on one or more of these services;
  * Partners with which we offer co-branded services, sell or distribute our products, or engage in joint marketing activities; and
  * Publicly-available sources such as open government databases or other data in the public domain.

The following are examples of information we have collected from other sources:

  * Name, postal address, email address and telephone number;
  * Demographic data, such as age, gender, and income level;
  * Your interests and purchase behavior;
  * Publicly-visible data, such as your posts and submissions to comments, blogs, video-sharing services, and other interactive forums; and
  * Other navigation data, such as web sites visited and advertisements viewed or clicked on.

For further information on Third Party Services, see the section entitled “Third Parties” below.

 **2.  How We Use the Information We Collect**

Our primary goal in collecting information is to provide you with a customized experience when using our Service and to make the Service more valuable to you. Because our Service is supported by advertising, we use the information we collect to help us and advertisers efficiently reach consumers who are most likely to be interested in particular products and services. We and our authorized Service Providers generally use information that we or they collect about you to:

  * Analyze, operate and improve our Service, and fulfill your requests for products, swag, services, and information, including to send you email and electronic newsletters;
  * Process your payments for purchases or requests for refunds, returns, or exchanges, as well as your redemption of discounts;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, information regarding changes to our policies, and support and administrative messages;
  * Prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities, comply with applicable law and enforce our terms;
  * Enable you to participate in features such as games, quizzes, surveys, polls, rankings, sweepstakes, and message boards;
  * Save and remember any preferences that you set while visiting part of our Service;
  * Customize the content you see when you use our Service and other services as you navigate online;
  * Attribute content that you post to comments and forums we operate on our Service;
  * Conduct market or audience analysis and related reporting;
  * Measure and analyze visitor traffic and usage patterns and improve the quality and effectiveness of our content, features, advertisements, and other communications;
  * Analyze how subscribers interact with our email messages and click on links contained within those messages;
  * Provide you with special offers, promotions and information from companies within our corporate family;
  * Tailor advertising to your interests, including advertising that you see on our Service, advertising you see on third-party websites, mobile applications and email programs, and offers and advertising you may receive offline or as push-notifications, from us or others;
  * Recognize the same users as they access online or mobile services using multiple browsers or devices and deliver to them appropriate interest-based content and advertising;
  * Provide you with special offers, promotions and information from select third parties in accordance with applicable law;
  * Develop and send you direct marketing, including advertisements and communications about our and third party products, offers, promotions, events, and services; and
  * Fulfill any other purposes disclosed to you with your consent.

We may use information that does not identify you (including information that has been de-identified) without obligation to you except as prohibited by applicable law. You always have the choice (now and in the future) to avoid personalized advertising based on your web browsing activity by visiting the DAA’s Consumer Choice page or the NAI’s website from each of your browsers or devices. For information on your rights and choices regarding how we use your information, please see the section entitled “Your Rights and Choices” below.

 **3\. Information Sharing**

We may disclose your personal information as follows:

  *  _Service Providers_. We may provide your personal information to our agents, vendors, and other service providers and companies (collectively “ **Service Providers** ”) that provide services to help us with our business activities such as customer service, payment processing, responding to inquiries about offerings, Promotions, or offering products, programs or services that may be of interest to you. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
  *  _Affiliates_. We may share your information with our related entities including our parent and sister companies. For example, we may share your information with our affiliates for customer support, marketing, and technical operations.
  *  _Business Partners_. We may share your information with our business partners in connection with offering you co-branded services, selling or distributing our products, or engaging in joint marketing activities.
  *  _Security and Compelled Disclosure_. We may share your information as required by law such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process. We may also share your information when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or respond to a government request.
  *  _Promotions_. If FanSided engages in a joint promotion with an affiliate and/or partner, we may share your contact information with our affiliate and/or partner to be used in relation to the promotion. We sometimes use this information to communicate with you, such as to notify you when you have won one of our contests or sweepstakes, when we make changes to subscriber agreements, to fulfill a request by you for an online newsletter, or to contact you about your account.
  *  _Third Parties_. We may disclose personally identifiable information that we receive from you and from third party sources to third parties whose practices are not covered by this privacy statement (e.g., other marketers, magazine publishers, retailers, participatory databases, and non-profit organizations) that want to market products or services to you. We may share your information with these third parties for purposes of facilitating your requests (such as when you choose to share information with a social network about your activities on the Service) and in connection with tailoring advertisements, measuring and improving our Service and advertising effectiveness, and enabling other enhancements.
  *  _Content_. If you choose to submit content (e.g., comments, a “letter to our editors” or an online post), we may publish your name, screen name and other information you have provided to us. You hereby consent to this. The information we collect in connection with our online forums and communities is used to provide an interactive experience. We use this information to facilitate participation in these online forums and communities and, from time to time, to offer you products, programs, or services.
  *  _Merger or Acquisition_. Please note that if FanSided or any of its subsidiaries or lines of business is merged, acquired, divested, financed, sold, disposed of or dissolved, including through merger of, consolidation, sale or divestiture of assets, the relevant customer database, including personally identifiable information we may possess about you, may, in whole or in part, be sold, disposed of, transferred, divested, or otherwise disclosed as part of that transaction or proceeding.
  *  _Consent_. We may share your information for any other purpose disclosed to you and with your consent.

We may share aggregated information which does not identify you (such as the number of daily visitors to a particular web page or the size of an order placed on a certain date) or de-identified information about you with third parties such as advertising partners without obligation to you for any purpose except as prohibited by applicable law. For information on your rights and choices regarding how we share your information, please see the section entitled “Your Rights and Choices” below.

 **4.  Third Parties**

 **A.     Collection of Information by Third-Party Services and Sponsors**

 **Third Party Services**. Some of our sites contain hyperlinks to other websites, locations, platforms, and services operated and owned by third parties (“ **Third Party Services** ”) whose information practices may be different than ours. FanSided also allows you to connect with other sites and services in order to share content and information. You should consult the other sites’ and services’ privacy notices, as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties or their use of your information.

 **Promotions**. FanSided sites sometimes may offer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, editorial features, or other activities or offerings that are sponsored or co-sponsored by or presented with identified third parties. By virtue of your participation in such activities or offerings, your IP address and the personally identifiable information that you voluntarily submit may be provided to both FanSided and the third parties. FanSided has no control over the third parties’ use of this information.

 **Advertising**. FanSided sites use reputable third parties to present or serve advertisements, including online behavioral advertisements, that you may see on the web pages or Apps and to conduct research about the advertisements. This Privacy Policy does not cover any use of information that such third parties may have collected from you (e.g., type of browser, operating system, domain name, day and time of visit, page(s) visited) or the methods used by the third-parties to collect that information (e.g., cookies, web beacons and clear gifs). For more information on tracking technologies and your rights and choices, see the section entitled “Your Rights and Choices” below.

 **B.     Third Party Features**

We may allow you to connect our Service to a Third Party Service or offer our Service through a Third Party Service (“ **Third Party Features** ”). If you use a Third Party Feature, both we and the applicable third party may have access to and use information associated with your use of the Third Party Feature, and you should carefully review the third party’s privacy policy and terms of use. Some examples of Third Party Features include the following:

 **Liking, Sharing, and Logging-In**. We may embed a pixel or SDK on our Service that allows you to “like” or “share” content on, or log-in to your FanSided account through, Third Party Services, including Disqus and social networks such as Facebook and Twitter. If you choose to engage with such a Third Party Service through our Service, we may collect any information you have authorized the Third Party Service to share with us (such as your user ID, billing information, public profile information, e-mail address, birthday, friends list, and other account and profile data). Likewise, if you choose to engage with such a Third Party Service through our Service or visit our Service while logged in to that Third Party Service on your device, the Third Party Service may receive information about your activities on our Service and be able to associate that information with information the Third Party Service already has about you.

 **Brand Pages**. We may offer our content on social networks such as a Facebook and Twitter. Any information you provide to us when you engage with our content (such as through our brand page) is treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Also, if you publicly reference our Service on a Third Party Service (e.g., by using a hashtag associated with Company in a tweet or post), we may use your reference on or in connection with our Service.

 **C.  Analytics and Interest-Based Advertising.**

Our Service contains Tracking Technologies owned and operated by Third Parties. For example, we use Tracking Technologies from third party analytics provides, such as Google Analytics, to help us analyze your use of the Service, compile statistic reports on the Service’s activity, and provide us with other services relating to Service activity and internet usage. We also work with ad serving services, advertisers, and other third parties to serve advertisements on the Service and/or on Third Party Services. These third parties may use Tracking Technologies on our Service and Third Party Services (including in e-mails and advertisements) to track your activities across time and services for purposes of associating the different devices you use, and delivering relevant ads and/or other content to you on the Service and Third Party Services or third party devices after you have left the Service (“Interest-based Advertising”).

We may serve ads on Third Party Services, such as Facebook and Google, which are targeted to reach people (or similar people) on those services that have visited our Service or that are also identified in one of more of our databases (“Matched Ads”). This is done by matching common factors between our data and the data of Third Party Services. If we use Facebook Custom Audiences to serve Matched Ads on Facebook services, you should be able to hover over the box in the right corner of such a Facebook ad and find out how to opt-out. We are not responsible for such Third Party Services’ failure to comply with your opt-out instructions.

For further information on Tracking Technologies and your rights and choices regarding them, please see the sections entitled “Information Collected Automatically” above and “Your Rights and Choices” below.

 **5.  Your Rights and Choices.**

 **A.     Review and Update of Account Information**

You may access, update, or remove certain account information that you have voluntarily submitted to us through the Service by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address set forth in the section entitled “Contact Us” below. We may require additional information from you to allow us to confirm your identity. Please note that we will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. California residents have additional rights as set forth in the sections entitled “Your California Privacy Rights.”

 **B.     Tracking Technology Choices**

  *  **Cookies and Pixels**. Most browsers accept cookies by default. You can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to decline or delete cookies. If you use multiple browsers on your device, you will need to instruct each browser separately. Your ability to limit cookies is subject to your browser settings and limitations. You may find that some parts of the site will not function properly if you have refused cookies or similar tracking technologies and you should be aware that disabling cookies or similar tracking technologies might prevent you from accessing some of our content. If you wish to block cookies, go to <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/> to find out how, or check your browser’s instructions.
  *  **Mobile App Advertising and Tracking**. We, our authorized Service Providers and/or other third-party partners involved in the delivery of advertising you receive through our mobile applications may collect information about your mobile device, including your mobile device’s advertising identifiers and the names and IDs of apps you have installed, as well as information about how you use our mobile applications and other unaffiliated applications. We and our partners use this information to enable interest-based advertising you receive through our Services and within third-party apps and other marketing channels. Depending on your device and operating system, you may be able to reset your mobile device’s advertising identifier to limit this data collection or prevent the collection of usage data across unaffiliated applications for interest-based advertising purposes by accessing the privacy settings on your mobile device. Each operating system, iOS for Apple devices, Android for Android devices and Windows for Microsoft devices, provides its own instructions. Visit the privacy settings for your mobile device or contact your platform operator for more information. To exercise choice over the companies participating in the DAA’s separate choice tool for the collection of cross-app data on a mobile device, download the DAA’s AppChoices app available [here](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices).
  *  **Location-Identifying Technologies**. The location data collected through an app depends on your device settings and app permissions. You can exercise choice over the location data collected through our apps by (i) for GPS data, disabling location in your device settings or disabling location permissions to that app; (ii) for Bluetooth data, disabling Bluetooth and any Bluetooth scanning option in your device settings; or (iii) for WiFi data, disabling WiFi and any WiFi scanning option in your device settings. You can stop collection of all location data via an app by uninstalling the app.
  *  **Do Not Track**. Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to online services you visit. Note, however, there is no industry consensus as to what site and app operators should do with regard to these signals. Accordingly, we do not monitor or take action with respect to “Do Not Track” signals or other mechanisms.  For more information on “Do Not Track,” visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/).

Please be aware that if you disable or remove Tracking Technologies some parts of the Service may not function correctly.

 **C.   Analytics and Interest-Based Advertising.**

Google, Adobe, and Salesforce DMP are some of the third parties we engage to track and analyze usage and browsing patterns of our users. For information about Google Analytics’ information practices and related opt-out choices, click [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). For information about Adobe’s information collection practices and related opt-out choices, click [here](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/marketing-cloud.html). For information about Salesforce DMP’s information collection practices and related opt-out choices, click [here](https://www.salesforce.com/products/marketing-cloud/sfmc/salesforce-dmp-consumer-choice/?mc=DMP). You can opt-out of your data being used by Google Analytics through cookies by visiting <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> and downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.

FanSided uses Google DoubleClick for Publishers and numerous other technology platforms to help deliver relevant advertising to you. Both FanSided and the technology service provider may collect, receive, or use your personal information in connection with FanSided’s use of the platform. For information about how Google uses data from DoubleClick for Publishers, click [here](https://support.google.com/admanager/answer/7670381). For a list of parties that may collect, receive, or use your personal information in connection with FanSided’s use of DoubleClick for Publishers and other platforms, click [here](https://fansided.com/privacy-policy/advertising-service-providers/).

FanSided follows the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral advertising released by the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) in July 2009. To opt-out of our use of your website viewing data to serve interest-based advertising on third-party websites and email newsletters, visit the DAA’s [Consumer Choice Page](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2&lang=EN). You can also click on the Ad Choices link located in the footer of our websites and navigate to the consumer opt-out form. Use the same links to opt-out of the delivery of interest-based advertising on our web sites from the operators of the third-party ad networks we use. Note that you must opt-out separately from each computer or device and browser that you use to access our Services and if you clear your cookies, you will need to repeat the opt-out process. Also note that the preferences you select on the DAA’s Consumer Choice Page do not apply to the collection of cross-app data from your mobile device. The DAA offers a separate choice tool for the collection of cross-app data on a mobile device for interest-based advertising and other applicable uses. To exercise choice for companies participating in this choice tool, you can install the DAA’s AppChoices app available [here](https://youradchoices.com/appchoices). Please also review the “Mobile App Advertising and Tracking” section above for additional choices.

Most of the third-party advertising and data companies we work with, including DoubleClick and Google, also subscribe to the DAA Principles and/or are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). To learn more about the information collection practices of NAI members and your related opt-out choices, please visit the NAI’s website [here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1). You can opt out of interest-based advertising from Google by visiting the [About Google Ads](https://support.google.com/ads/troubleshooter/1631343?hl=en&visit_id=636856140830744980-2766415109&rd=1) page or opt out of the DoubleClick cookie by installing the [DoubleClick opt out extension](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996).

 **D.    Communications.**

  *  **E-mails**. You can opt-out of receiving promotional e-mails from us at any time by following the instructions as provided in e-mails to click on the unsubscribe link, or e-mailing us at the e-mail address set forth in the section entitled “Contact Us” below with the word UNSUBSCRIBE in the subject field of the e-mail. Please note that you cannot opt-out of non-promotional e-mails, such as those about your account, transactions, servicing, or FanSided’s ongoing business relations.
  *  **Push Notifications**. If you have opted-in to receive push notification on your device, you can opt-out at any time by adjusting the permissions in your device or uninstalling our app.

Please note that your opt-out is limited to the e-mail address, device, and phone number used and will not affect subsequent subscriptions.

 **E.   Your California Privacy Rights.**

California’s “Shine the Light” law permits customers in California to request certain details about how certain types of their information are shared with third parties and, in some cases, affiliates, for those third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. Under the law, a business should either provide California customers certain information upon request or permit California customers to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing.

FanSided may share personal information as defined by California’s “Shine the Light” law with third parties and/or affiliates for such third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and wish to obtain information about our compliance with this law, please contact us as set forth in the section entitled “Contact Us” below. Requests must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that FanSided is not required to respond to requests made by means other than through the provided e-mail address or mail address.

Any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use the Service and posted content or information on the Service, can request that such information be removed from the Service by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address set forth in the section entitled “Contact Us” below. Requests must state that the user personally posted such content or information and detail where the content or information is posted. We will make reasonable good faith efforts to remove the post from prospective public view.

 **6.  Security**

We maintain administrative, technical, and physical safeguards in an effort to protect against unauthorized access, use, loss, modification, disclosure, and any form of unlawful processing of personal information in our custody and control, and our service providers are bound to maintain similar safeguards. These measures also aim at preventing unnecessary collection and further processing of personal information.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

 **7.  Children**

The Service is intended for a general audience and not directed to children under thirteen (13) years of age. FanSided does not knowingly collect personal information as defined by the U.S. Children’s Privacy Protection Act (“ **COPPA** ”) in a manner that is not permitted by COPPA. If you are a parent or guardian and believe FanSided has collected such information in a manner not permitted by COPPA, please email us at support@fansided.com and we will remove such data to the extent required by COPPA.

 **8.  Notification of Privacy Policy Changes**

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. The revised Privacy Policy will be posted on this website with the date of the last modification. We will treat your personal information in accordance with the privacy policy in place at the time of collection of such information, or as you otherwise indicate your preferences. We encourage you to periodically review this policy for the latest information on our privacy practices.

 **Contact Us:**  
You can contact us about this Privacy Policy, our data practices, or our compliance with applicable law by writing or emailing us at the address below:  
support@fansided.com  
FanSided, Inc., 225 Liberty Street, New York, NY 10281
